<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"><metadata>  <idinfo>    <citation>      <citeinfo>        <origin>SPOT Image Corporation</origin>        <pubdate>2009</pubdate>        <title>Dar es Salaam region, Tanzania, 10m multispectral SPOT satellite image data, June 2009</title>        <geoform>SDE raster digital data</geoform>        <pubinfo>          <pubplace>Chantilly, Virginia</pubplace>          <publish>SPOT Image Corporation</publish>        </pubinfo>        <othercit>SPOT filename: 51463640906240734482JMap name: SCENE 5 146-364/0 09/06/24 07:34:48 2 J</othercit>        <onlink>http://hgl.hul.harvard.edu:8080/HGL/jsp/HGL.jsp?action=VColl&amp;VCollName=SPOT_51463640906240734482J</onlink>      </citeinfo>    </citation>    <descript>      <abstract>10 meter resolution multispectral (color) SPOT 5 satellite image data of the Dar es Salaam region, Tanzania, collected June 24, 2009.</abstract>      <purpose>SPOT images can be directly integrated  in image processing, geographic information or map-making systems. They can be processed and combined with other geographic data  to extract whatever information may be needed for studying, monitoring, forecasting and managing natural resources and human activities.</purpose>    </descript>    <timeperd>      <timeinfo>        <sngdate>          <caldate>20090624</caldate>        </sngdate>      </timeinfo>      <current>ground condition</current>    </timeperd>    <status>      <progress>Complete</progress>      <update>None planned</update>    </status>    <spdom>      <bounding>        <westbc>39.120091</westbc>        <eastbc>39.358956</eastbc>        <northbc>-6.709693</northbc>        <southbc>-6.941839</southbc>      </bounding>    </spdom>    <keywords>      <theme>        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>        <themekey>Remote-sensing images</themekey>        <themekey>Earth Surface</themekey>        <themekey>Land use</themekey>      </theme>      <theme>        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>      </theme>      <place>        <placekt>GNS</placekt>        <placekey>Tanzania</placekey>        <placekey>Dar es Salaam</placekey>      </place>    </keywords>    <accconst>Access is granted to Harvard University Affiliates only.  Affiliates are limited to current faculty, staff and students.</accconst>    <useconst>NON-EXCLUSIVE LICENSE TO USE SPOT SATELLITE PRODUCTS BETWEEN SPOT IMAGE CORPORATION (SICORP) AND THE END-USER   The END-USER accepts and agrees to be bound by the terms of this End-User License Agreement ("EULA") by doing any of the following: (a) accepting, in whole or in part, a quotation for the supply of the PRODUCT; (b) breaking the seal on the package containing the PRODUCT; (c) downloading and/or installing and/or manipulating the PRODUCT on any computer; (d) paying in whole or in part the Product (e) damaging or destroying the PRODUCT; (f) retaining the PRODUCT for more than 7 days following receipt thereof.  ARTICLE 1 - DEFINITIONS  "DERIVATIVE WORKS": means any derivative product or information developed by the END-USER from the PRODUCT, which does not contain any imagery data from the PRODUCT and is irreversible and uncoupled from the source imagery data of the PRODUCT. Notwithstanding the foregoing, by express exception, any Digital Elevation Model or Digital Terrain Model (in any form whatsoever, i.e. database for instance) derived from a PRODUCT shall never be considered as DERIVATIVE WORKS.  "END-USER": means the University which is supplied with the PRODUCT and accepts this EULA. When the PRODUCT is supplied to a University with multiple campuses, the END-USER shall be deemed to be only such part of the University as located at the address to which the PRODUCT is supplied, except upon SICORP prior agreement in writing.  "PRODUCT": means the SPOT satellite product(s) supplied by SICORP to the END-USER.  "VAP": means any product developed by the END-USER, which contains imagery data from the PRODUCT, and resulting in a significant modification of the PRODUCT, through technical manipulations and/or addition of other data. Notwithstanding the foregoing, by express exception, any Digital Elevation Model or Digital Terrain Model derived from a PRODUCT shall always be considered as a VAP.  ARTICLE 2 - LICENSE  2.1 Permitted Uses  The END-USER is hereby granted by SICORP a limited, non-exclusive, non transferable, License: (a) to install the PRODUCT on as many individual computers as needed in its premises, including internal computer network (with the express exclusion of the internet, except as provided under paragraph (g) below) for the Permitted Uses under paragraphs (b) to (i) below; (b) to make a maximum of ten (10) copies for (I) installation of the PRODUCT as per paragraph (a) above and (II) archiving and back-up purposes; (c) to use the PRODUCT for internal University research purposes only; (d) to alter or modify the PRODUCT to produce VAPs and/or DERIVATIVE WORKS for internal University research purposes only; (e) to post one extract, maximum size 1024 x 1024 pixels, of any PRODUCT or VAP on an internet site, in an internet-compatible image format (without associated metadata), with the following credit conspicuously displayed: "includes material © CNES _____(year of production), Distribution SPOT Image Corp., USA, all rights reserved" written in full. Such posting shall be used for END-USER research purposes only (and only if such research does not relate to the provision of online mapping and location-based services), and may in no event allow downloading of the extract posted, nor be used to distribute, sell, assign, dispose of, lease, sublicense or transfer such extract. Prior to any posting, the END-USER shall inform SICORP, specifying the URL address used by END-USER: sales@spot.com; (f) to print any extract, maximum size 1024 x 1024 pixels, of a PRODUCT or a VAP, and to distribute such print for research purposes only. Such print shall include the following credit conspicuously displayed: "includes material © CNES _____(year of production), Distribution SPOT Image Corp., USA, all rights reserved" written in full. All rights not expressly granted by SICORP under the present Article 2.1 are hereby retained by SICORP.  2.2 Prohibited Uses  The END-USER recognizes and agrees that the PRODUCT is and shall remain the property of SICORP, and contains proprietary information of SICORP and thus is provided to the END-USER on a confidential basis.  The END-USER shall not, do any of the following: (a) do anything not expressly authorized under Article 2.1; and (b) alter or remove any copyright notice or proprietary legend contained in or on the PRODUCTS.      ARTICLE 3 - INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS  3.1 The satellite imagery data contained in the PRODUCT are the property of Centre National d'Etudes Spatiales (CNES), France. 3.2 The PRODUCT is protected by French and international copyright laws. 3.3 In addition, the PRODUCT and the satellite imagery data contained therein are protected by articles L 341-1 to 343-4 of the French Code of Intellectual Property Law as amended by the statute of 1 July 1998, relative to database copyright and to similar statutes in European countries that have incorporated EU Directive n° 96/9 of 11 March 1996 on database copyright into their laws.  ARTICLE 4 - WARRANTY - LIABILITY  4.1 SICORP warrants that it has sufficient ownership rights in the PRODUCT to make the PRODUCT available to the END-USER under the terms thereof. 4.2 The PRODUCT is complex; SICORP does not warrant that the PRODUCT is free of bugs, errors, defects or omissions, and that operation of the PRODUCT will be error free or uninterrupted nor that all non-conformities will or can be corrected. It does not warrant that the PRODUCT shall meet the END-USER's requirements or expectations, or shall be fit for the END-USER's intended purposes. There are no express or implied warranties of fitness or merchantability given in connection with the sale or use of this PRODUCT. SICORP disclaims all other warranties not expressly provided in Articles 4.1 and 4.2. In case the medium on which the PRODUCT is supplied by SICORP to the END-USER is deficient, as demonstrated by the END-USER and accepted by SICORP, SICORP shall replace said medium. Any such claim for replacement shall be notified to SICORP within seven (7) days after delivery of the PRODUCT to the END-USER. 4.3 In no event shall SICORP, nor anybody having contributed to development and/or production and/or delivery of the PRODUCT, be liable for any claim, damage or loss incurred by the END-USER, including without limitation indirect, compensatory, consequential, incidental, special, incorporeal or exemplary damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the PRODUCT, and shall not be subject to legal action in this respect.  The financial cumulative liability of SICORP and of anybody having contributed to developing and/or production and/or delivery of the PRODUCT is limited to distribution of the PRODUCT and shall not in any case exceed the price paid by the END-USER to purchase the PRODUCT.  ARTICLE 5 - MISCELLANEOUS  5.1 This End-User License Agreement shall run for an unlimited term. SICORP may, in addition to all other remedies to which it may be entitled under this EULA or at law, terminate immediately this EULA by notice in writing if the END-USER breaches any provision of this EULA. The END-USER shall have no claim to any kind of refund in this case. Upon termination, the END-USER shall return to SICORP the PRODUCTS and VAPs. 5.2 The END-USER shall not transfer part or all of this EULA without SICORP's prior written consent. 5.3 In the event that any provision of this EULA is declared invalid or unenforceable, the remaining provisions of this EULA shall be applicable. 5.4 This End-User License Agreement is governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Virginia. All disputes shall be referred to the courts of Virginia.</useconst>    <ptcontac>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>SPOT Image Corporation</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>          <address>14595 Avion Parkway, Suite 500</address>          <city>Chantilly</city>          <state>Virginia</state>          <postal>20151</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>(703) 715-3100</cntvoice>        <cntfax>(703) 715-3120</cntfax>        <cntemail>sales@spot.com</cntemail>      </cntinfo>    </ptcontac>    <native>ArcGIS 9.3</native>    <crossref>      <citeinfo>        <origin>SPOT Image Corporation</origin>        <pubdate>2009</pubdate>        <title>Dar es Salaam region, Tanzania, 2.5m panchromatic SPOT satellite image data, June 2009</title>        <geoform>SDE raster digital data</geoform>        <pubinfo>          <pubplace>Chantilly, Virginia</pubplace>          <publish>SPOT Image Corporation</publish>        </pubinfo>        <othercit>SPOT filename: 51463640906240734462BMap name: SCENE 5 146-364 09/06/24 07:34:45 2 T</othercit>        <onlink>http://hgl.harvard.edu</onlink>      </citeinfo>    </crossref>  </idinfo>  <dataqual>    <attracc>      <attraccr>Unknown</attraccr>    </attracc>    <logic>Unknown</logic>    <complete>Unknown</complete>    <posacc>      <horizpa>        <horizpar>30 m.</horizpar>      </horizpa>    </posacc>    <lineage>      <srcinfo>        <srccite>          <citeinfo>            <origin>SPOT Image Corporation</origin>            <pubdate>2009</pubdate>            <title>SPOT image : 51463640906240734482J</title>            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>            <pubinfo>              <pubplace>Chantilly, Virginia</pubplace>              <publish>SPOT Image Corporation</publish>            </pubinfo>          </citeinfo>        </srccite>        <typesrc>online</typesrc>        <srctime>          <timeinfo>            <sngdate>              <caldate>20090624</caldate>            </sngdate>          </timeinfo>          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>        </srctime>        <srccitea>SPOT image</srccitea>        <srccontr>Source 10m image</srccontr>      </srcinfo>      <procstep>        <procdesc>Geometric Processing Level : PRECISION 2A 	level 1A: Radiometric correction of distortions due to differences in sensitivity of the elementary detectors of the viewing instrument. Intended for users who wish to do their own geometric image processing.level 2A: Radiometric correction identical to that of level 1A. Geometrical correction done in a standard cartographic projection (UTM WGS84 by default) not tied to ground control points.Image capture specs:Scene ID 	5 146-364 09/06/24 07:34:48 2 J K-J identification 	146-364 Date 	2009-06-24 07:34:48.1 Instrument 	HRG 2 Shift Along Track 	0 8 Preprocessing level 	2A Spectral mode 	J Number of spectral bands 	4 Spectral band indicator 	HI1 	HI2 	HI3 	HI4 Gain number 	8 	8 	5 	5 Absolute calibration gains 	2.777650 	3.809955 	1.706650 	10.618743 (1/W*m2*sr*µm) 	Orientation angle 	13.004795 degree Incidence angle 	R12.480697 degree Sun angles (degree) 	Azimut: 40.487409 Elevation: 49.411234 Number of lines 	2565 Number of pixels per line 	2638 Location in the full scene 	Top left corner 	Pixel: 1308 Line: 281 Bottom right corner 	Pixel: 3945 Line: 2845</procdesc>        <procdate>2009</procdate>        <srcprod>SPOT image</srcprod>        <proccont>          <cntinfo>            <cntorgp>              <cntorg>SPOT Image Corporation</cntorg>            </cntorgp>            <cntaddr>              <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>              <address>14595 Avion Parkway, Suite 500</address>              <city>Chantilly</city>              <state>Virginia</state>              <postal>20151</postal>              <country>USA</country>            </cntaddr>            <cntvoice>(703) 715-3100</cntvoice>            <cntfax>(703) 715-3120</cntfax>            <cntemail>sales@spot.com</cntemail>          </cntinfo>        </proccont>      </procstep>      <procstep>        <procdesc>This SPOT satellite image was downloaded from the SPOT Image Corporation's ftp website.  It was then imported to an ArcSDE 9.1 geodatabase using the "Raster to Geodatabase" tool in ArcCatalog 9.3.</procdesc>        <srcused>multispectral SPOT</srcused>        <procdate>2009</procdate>        <srcprod>SPOT_51463640906240734482J</srcprod>        <proccont>          <cntinfo>            <cntorgp>              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>            </cntorgp>            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>            <cntaddr>              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>              <address>Harvard University Library</address>              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>              <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>              <city>Cambridge</city>              <state>MA</state>              <postal>02138</postal>              <country>USA</country>            </cntaddr>            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>          </cntinfo>        </proccont>      </procstep>    </lineage>  </dataqual>  <spdoinfo>    <direct>Raster</direct>    <rastinfo>      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>      <rowcount>2565</rowcount>      <colcount>2638</colcount>      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>    </rastinfo>  </spdoinfo>  <spref>    <horizsys>      <planar>        <gridsys>          <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn>          <utm>            <utmzone>-37</utmzone>            <transmer>              <sfctrmer>0.999600</sfctrmer>              <longcm>39.000000</longcm>              <latprjo>0.000000</latprjo>              <feast>500000.000000</feast>              <fnorth>10000000.000000</fnorth>            </transmer>          </utm>        </gridsys>        <planci>          <plance>row and column</plance>          <coordrep>            <absres>10.000000</absres>            <ordres>10.000000</ordres>          </coordrep>          <plandu>meters</plandu>        </planci>      </planar>      <geodetic>        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>      </geodetic>    </horizsys>  </spref>  <eainfo>    <overview>      <eaover>Each pixel is coded with three 8-bit values representing the amounts of Red, Green, and Blue in the pixel. This produces a 24-bit RGB image. 8-bit (values ranging 0-255) Red, Green, and Blue values are packed into a single 24-bit identity. This allows for a maximum of 16,777,216 unique combinations of colors.  The colors in the image can represent ground features such as drainage, vegetation, cultural features, coastal hydrography, transportation features (roads, railroads, tracks and trails) and more. In addition to RGB values SPOT 5 data also includes a Band 4 value for each pixel representing shortwave infrared (B4 (SWIR): 1.58-1.75 µm). Each pixel represents approximately 10 meters ground resolution.</eaover>      <eadetcit>Not applicable.</eadetcit>    </overview>  </eainfo>  <distinfo>    <distrib>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>          <address>Harvard University Library</address>          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>          <city>Cambridge</city>          <state>MA</state>          <postal>02138</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>      </cntinfo>    </distrib>    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>    <distliab>Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>    <stdorder>      <digform>        <digtinfo>          <formname>Raster Grid</formname>        </digtinfo>        <digtopt>          <onlinopt>            <computer>              <networka>                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>              </networka>            </computer>          </onlinopt>        </digtopt>      </digform>      <fees>None</fees>      <ordering>Web-based distribution only</ordering>    </stdorder>  </distinfo>  <metainfo>    <metd>20091001</metd>    <metc>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>          <address>Harvard University Library</address>          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>          <address>90 Mount Auburn Street</address>          <city>Cambridge</city>          <state>MA</state>          <postal>02138</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>      </cntinfo>    </metc>    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>    <mettc>local time</mettc>  </metainfo></metadata>