<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"><metadata>  <idinfo>    <citation>      <citeinfo>        <origin>ISciences (Firm)</origin>        <origin>Shuttle Radar Topography Mission</origin>        <pubdate>2003</pubdate>        <title>SRTM30 enhanced global map : Elevation</title>        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>        <pubinfo>          <pubplace>[Ann Arbor, Mich.]</pubplace>          <publish>ISciences</publish>        </pubinfo>        <onlink>http://hgl.harvard.edu:8080/HGL/jsp/HGL.jsp?action=VColl&amp;VCollName=SRTM30_ELEVATION30</onlink>        <lworkcit>          <citeinfo>            <origin>ISciences (Firm)</origin>            <origin>Shuttle Radar Topography Mission.</origin>            <pubdate>2003</pubdate>            <title>TerraViva! SRTM30 global enhanced : elevation, slope, aspect</title>            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>            <pubinfo>              <pubplace>[Ann Arbor, Mich.]</pubplace>              <publish>ISciences</publish>            </pubinfo>            <othercit>2 CD-ROMs.Disc 1. Slope &amp; elevation -- Disc 2. Aspect &amp; source.</othercit>          </citeinfo>        </lworkcit>      </citeinfo>    </citation>    <descript>      <abstract>This raster grid datalayer consists of global 30 arc-second resolution elevation data derived from SRTM30 (Shuttle Radar Topography Mission) data, supplemented with GTOPO30 elevation data, ETOPO2 depth data, and other data sources.  Elevation values are represented in meters above or below mean sea level. The datalayer was produced by ISciences and published in 2003 as part of the TerraViva! SRTM30 global enhanced : elevation, slope and aspect, data set.  SRTM30 data was collected February 11-22, 2000.From the ISciences Web site:"SRTM30 Enhanced Global Map is a global elevation and depth data set from ISciences at 30 arc-second resolution that includes an elevation map, slope angle map, slope aspect map, and source map. Each pixel represents an area ranging from one sixth of a square mile at 60 degrees to one third of a square mile at the equator. To get a view of your world as good as this you'd need a map 18 feet high and 36 feet wide! SRTM30 Enhanced Global Map was created by combining 27 SRTM30 elevation files, identifying and correcting anomalies, supplementing with elevation data from an alternate source for land areas not included in SRTM30, and adding depth data. The result -- a beautifully blended, high-quality, stunning global elevation and depth map suitable for display at scales to1:3,000,000."</abstract>      <purpose>The ISciences enhanced global map data builds on SRTM data by offering a global composite, complete global coverage elevation dataset with rectified anomalies, computed slope and aspect data, and additional depth data.From SRTM Web site:"The objective of the SRTM project is to produce digital topographic data for 80% of the Earth's land surface (all land areas between 60° north and 56° south latitude), with data points located every 1-arc-second (approximately 30 meters) on a latitude/longitude grid.  The absolute vertical accuracy of the elevation data will be 16 meters (at 90% confidence). This radar system will gather data that will result in the most accurate and complete topographic map of the Earth's surface that has ever been assembled.What can the data be used for?Space Shuttle Landing.These data can be tailored to meet the needs of the military, civil, and scientific user communities. But other uses of this data include improved water drainage modeling, more realistic flight simulators, better locations for cell phone towers, navigation safety, and even improved maps for backpackers.Just about any project that requires accurate knowledge of the shape and height of the land can benefit from this data. Some examples are flood control, soil conservation, reforestation, volcano monitoring, earthquake research, and glacier movement monitoring."</purpose>    </descript>    <timeperd>      <timeinfo>        <rngdates>          <begdate>20000211</begdate>          <enddate>20000222</enddate>        </rngdates>      </timeinfo>      <current>ground condition</current>    </timeperd>    <status>      <progress>Complete</progress>      <update>None planned</update>    </status>    <spdom>      <bounding>        <westbc>-180.000000</westbc>        <eastbc>180.000000</eastbc>        <northbc>90.000000</northbc>        <southbc>-90.000000</southbc>      </bounding>    </spdom>    <keywords>      <theme>        <themekt>LCSH</themekt>        <themekey>Altitudes</themekey>        <themekey>Topographic maps</themekey>        <themekey>Remote sensing maps</themekey>        <themekey>Earth Surface</themekey>        <themekey>Slopes (Physical geography)</themekey>        <themekey>World maps</themekey>        <themekey>World maps, physical</themekey>      </theme>      <theme>        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>        <themekey>elevation</themekey>        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>      </theme>      <place>        <placekt>LCSH</placekt>        <placekey>Earth</placekey>        <placekey>Eastern Hemisphere</placekey>        <placekey>Western Hemisphere</placekey>        <placekey>Northern Hemisphere</placekey>        <placekey>Southern Hemisphere</placekey>        <placekey>Africa</placekey>        <placekey>Asia</placekey>        <placekey>Australia</placekey>        <placekey>Europe</placekey>        <placekey>North America</placekey>        <placekey>South America</placekey>        <placekey>Polar regions</placekey>      </place>    </keywords>    <accconst>Available only to Harvard University affiliates. Affiliates are limited to current faculty, staff and students.</accconst>    <useconst>The data are provided under the terms of Harvard University Institutional Network License.  These data must be used in compliance with the Network License:NOTICE TO USERS: Use of the data and information provided with this agreement (the "product") constitutes your acceptance of these terms.  If you do not agree to the terms of this agreement, promptly remove the product together with all copies from your computer and return the product along with the invoice within ninety (90) days of receipt to ISCIENCES, L.L.C. (300 North Fifth Avenue, Suite 120, Ann Arbor, MI 48104 USA).  Your use of this product is conditioned upon compliance with the terms of this agreement.LICENSE: ISCIENCES, L.L.C. (ISci) grants you a non-exclusive, non-transferable right to use the product on a campus-wide or institution-wide network.  This license to use the product is conditioned upon your compliance with the terms of this agreement.  This license is effective until terminated.  You may terminate it at any point by returning the product and destroying all copies of the product.  ISci has the option to terminate this license if you fail to comply with any term or condition of this agreement.  You agree upon such termination to return the product and destroy all copies of the product.  COPYRIGHT:  The product is protected by United States copyright law and international treaty provisions.  You acknowledge that no title to the intellectual property in the product is transferred to you.  You further acknowledge that title and full ownership rights to the product will remain the exclusive property of ISci.  You do not acquire any right to the product except as expressly set forth in this license.REVERSE ENGINEERING: You agree that you will not attempt to reverse compile, modify, translate, or disassemble the product except as needed to use it in its intended manner.GOVERNING LAW: This agreement shall be governed by the laws of the State of Michigan.DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY:  This product is provided on an "as is" basis without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement.  The entire risk as to the quality and performance of the product is borne by you.  Should the product prove defective you, and not ISci, assume the entire cost of any service and repair.  This disclaimer of warranty constitutes an essential part of the agreement.  Some states do not allow exclusions of an implied warranty, so this disclaimer may not apply to you and you may have other legal rights that vary from state to state or by jurisdiction.LIMITATION OF LIABILITY:  Under no circumstances and under no legal theory, tort, contract, or otherwise, shall ISci be liable to you or any other person for any indirect, special incidental, or consequential damages of any character including, without limitation, damages for loss of goodwill, work stoppage, computer failure or malfunction, or any and all other commercial damages or losses.  In no event will ISci be liable for any damages in excess of purchase price for a license to the product, even if ISci has been informed of the possibility of such damages, or for any claim by any other party.  Some states do not allow the exclusion or limitation of incidental or consequential damages, so this limitation and exclusion may not apply to you.</useconst>    <ptcontac>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>ISciences</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>          <address>300 N. Fifth Ave., Suite 120</address>          <city>Ann Arbor</city>          <state>MI</state>          <postal>48104</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>734-214-9810</cntvoice>        <cntfax>734-214-9813</cntfax>        <cntemail>info@terraviva.net</cntemail>      </cntinfo>    </ptcontac>    <native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.1.0.722</native>    <crossref>      <citeinfo>        <origin>Rodriguez, Ernesto</origin>        <origin>Jet Propulsion Laboratory (U.S.)</origin>        <pubdate>2005</pubdate>        <title>An assessment of the SRTM topographic products</title>        <geoform>document</geoform>        <serinfo>          <sername>Jet Propulsion Laboratory (U.S.). Technical Report</sername>          <issue>D-31639</issue>        </serinfo>        <pubinfo>          <pubplace>Pasadena, California</pubplace>          <publish>Jet Propulsion Laboratory</publish>        </pubinfo>        <othercit>E. Rodriguez, et. al</othercit>        <onlink>http://www2.jpl.nasa.gov/srtm/SRTM_D31639.pdf</onlink>      </citeinfo>    </crossref>  </idinfo>  <dataqual>    <attracc>      <attraccr>For SRTM data: See SRTM accuracy report: An assessment of the SRTM topographic products.</attraccr>    </attracc>    <logic>For SRTM data: See SRTM accuracy report: An assessment of the SRTM topographic products.</logic>    <complete>For SRTM data: See SRTM accuracy report: An assessment of the SRTM topographic products.</complete>    <posacc>      <horizpa>        <horizpar>For SRTM data: See SRTM accuracy report: An assessment of the SRTM topographic products.</horizpar>      </horizpa>      <vertacc>        <vertaccr>For SRTM data: See SRTM accuracy report: An assessment of the SRTM topographic products.</vertaccr>      </vertacc>    </posacc>    <lineage>      <srcinfo>        <srccite>          <citeinfo>            <origin>Jet Propulsion Laboratory (U.S.)</origin>            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>            <title>Shuttle Radar Topography Mission : 30 arc-second data</title>            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>            <pubinfo>              <pubplace>Pasadena, California</pubplace>              <publish>Jet Propulsion Laboratory</publish>            </pubinfo>          </citeinfo>        </srccite>        <typesrc>online</typesrc>        <srctime>          <timeinfo>            <rngdates>              <begdate>20000211</begdate>              <enddate>20000222</enddate>            </rngdates>          </timeinfo>          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>        </srctime>        <srccitea>SRTM data</srccitea>        <srccontr>Original elevation data source</srccontr>      </srcinfo>      <srcinfo>        <srccite>          <citeinfo>            <origin>Geological Survey (U.S.)</origin>            <pubdate>1996</pubdate>            <title>GOTOPO30 : Global 30 arc second elevation data</title>            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>            <pubinfo>              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>              <publish>EROS Data Center</publish>            </pubinfo>          </citeinfo>        </srccite>        <typesrc>online</typesrc>        <srctime>          <timeinfo>            <sngdate>              <caldate>1996</caldate>            </sngdate>          </timeinfo>          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>        </srctime>        <srccitea>GOTOPO30 data</srccitea>        <srccontr>Supplemental elevation data source for land areas not available in SRTM30.</srccontr>      </srcinfo>      <srcinfo>        <srccite>          <citeinfo>            <origin>National Geophysical Data Center</origin>            <pubdate>2001</pubdate>            <title>2-minute gridded global relief data (ETOPO2)</title>            <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>            <pubinfo>              <pubplace>Boulder, Colo.</pubplace>              <publish>National Geophysical Data Center</publish>            </pubinfo>          </citeinfo>        </srccite>        <typesrc>online</typesrc>        <srctime>          <timeinfo>            <sngdate>              <caldate>2001</caldate>            </sngdate>          </timeinfo>          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>        </srctime>        <srccitea>ETOPO2 data</srccitea>        <srccontr>Supplemental depth data source.</srccontr>      </srcinfo>      <procstep>        <procdesc>The Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) gathered 12 terabytes of raw elevation data over a period of 10 days [February 11-22, 2000], covering 80% of the earth's land surface [60 degrees north latitude to 60 degress south latitude].  NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory then processed the data to 30 arc-second resolution producing 27 tiles. Recognizing the potential uses for a uniformly blended global composite of elevation data combined with depth data, ISciences first scrubbed the SRTM30 data to insure pixel-by-pixel reliability. Anomalies in the SRTM data were identified and remedied using best-source correction and specially developed leveling techniques. These anomalies included elevation "step" anomalies measuring in the tens to hundreds of meters, lake surface data anomalies, and "wells," inconsistently depressed areas. ISciences stitched the corrected SRTM tiles together, then supplemented with GTOPO30 elevation data for land areas absent from SRTM30. And finally, to increase the utility of its new product, ISciences enhanced the corrected and blended elevation data with the addition of depth data from ETOPO2.</procdesc>        <srcused>SRTM data</srcused>        <srcused>GOTOPO30 data</srcused>        <srcused>ETOPO2 data</srcused>        <procdate>Unknown</procdate>        <srcprod>ISciences data</srcprod>        <proccont>          <cntinfo>            <cntorgp>              <cntorg>ISciences</cntorg>            </cntorgp>            <cntaddr>              <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>              <address>300 N. Fifth Ave., Suite 120</address>              <city>Ann Arbor</city>              <state>MI</state>              <postal>48104</postal>              <country>USA</country>            </cntaddr>            <cntvoice>734-214-9810</cntvoice>            <cntfax>734-214-9813</cntfax>            <cntemail>info@terraviva.net</cntemail>          </cntinfo>        </proccont>      </procstep>      <procstep>        <procdesc>This layer was originally downloaded from the ISciences CD and then imported from ESRI GRID format to an ArcSDE 9.1 geodatabase using the "Raster to Geodatabase" tool in ArcCatalog 9.1.</procdesc>        <srcused>ISciences data</srcused>        <procdate>200606</procdate>        <proccont>          <cntinfo>            <cntorgp>              <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>            </cntorgp>            <cntpos>GIS Technician</cntpos>            <cntaddr>              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>              <address>Office for Information Systems</address>              <address>Harvard University Library</address>              <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>              <city>Cambridge</city>              <state>MA</state>              <postal>02138</postal>              <country>USA</country>            </cntaddr>            <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>            <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>            <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>            <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>          </cntinfo>        </proccont>      </procstep>    </lineage>  </dataqual>  <spdoinfo>    <direct>Raster</direct>    <rastinfo>      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>      <rowcount>21600</rowcount>      <colcount>43200</colcount>      <vrtcount>1</vrtcount>    </rastinfo>  </spdoinfo>  <spref>    <horizsys>      <geograph>        <latres>0.000001</latres>        <longres>0.000001</longres>        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>      </geograph>      <geodetic>        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>      </geodetic>    </horizsys>    <vertdef>      <altsys>        <altdatum>WGS_1984</altdatum>        <altres>1</altres>        <altunits>meters</altunits>        <altenc>Attribute values</altenc>      </altsys>      <depthsys>        <depthdn>Mean sea level</depthdn>        <depthres>1</depthres>        <depthdu>meters</depthdu>        <depthem>Attribute values</depthem>      </depthsys>    </vertdef>  </spref>  <eainfo>    <overview>      <eaover>Cell units are in meters above/below sea level.</eaover>      <eadetcit>ISciences, L.L.C.  TerraViva! SRTM30 global enhanced : elevation, slope, aspect. readme_elvdepthtxt file.  Ann Arbor, MI, 2003.</eadetcit>    </overview>  </eainfo>  <distinfo>    <distrib>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>          <address>Harvard University Library</address>          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>          <city>Cambridge</city>          <state>MA</state>          <postal>02138</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>      </cntinfo>    </distrib>    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>    <distliab>Although this data is being distributed by Harvard University, no warranty expressed or implied is made by the University as to the accuracy of the data and related materials. The act of distribution shall not constitute any such warranty, and no responsibility is assumed by the University in the use of this data, or related materials.</distliab>    <stdorder>      <digform>        <digtinfo>          <formname>ESRI Grid</formname>          <filedec>ZIP</filedec>        </digtinfo>        <digtopt>          <onlinopt>            <computer>              <networka>                <networkr>http://hgl.harvard.edu/</networkr>              </networka>            </computer>          </onlinopt>        </digtopt>      </digform>      <fees>None</fees>      <ordering>Web-based distribution only</ordering>    </stdorder>  </distinfo>  <metainfo>    <metd>20060825</metd>    <metc>      <cntinfo>        <cntorgp>          <cntorg>Harvard Geospatial Library</cntorg>        </cntorgp>        <cntpos>Geospatial Resources Cataloger</cntpos>        <cntaddr>          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>          <address>Harvard University Library</address>          <address>Office For Information Systems</address>          <address>1280 Massachusetts Avenue</address>          <city>Cambridge</city>          <state>MA</state>          <postal>02138</postal>          <country>USA</country>        </cntaddr>        <cntvoice>617-495-2417</cntvoice>        <cntfax>617-496-0440</cntfax>        <cntemail>hgl_ref@hulmail.harvard.edu</cntemail>        <hours>Monday - Friday, 9:00 am - 4:00 pm EST-USA</hours>      </cntinfo>    </metc>    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>    <mettc>local time</mettc>    <metextns>      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>    </metextns>  </metainfo></metadata>